{
    "id": "5a66182f09aa42f996ed991acd177c3a",
    "title": "If-Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………… respect, you get respect.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "give",
                "will give",
                "would give"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "86371905f0e446529168759c9d0c2f37"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she studies well, she …………………………. good marks.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will get",
                "gets",
                "would get"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "89581816cd1f4872ba03f049a7a782d6"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ……………………………. to earn more money, you have to work harder.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "want",
                "wanted",
                "had wanted"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "744c8bebac044d4aaf1981c24773823d"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………….. him, tell him that I am waiting for him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "meet",
                "met",
                "had met"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b8326224b2e64548adfe69c0ff6b70d4"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………….. out, you will not lose that belly fat.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "don't work",
                "didn't work",
                "hadn't worked"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9622f387838e4c5a9469fca77e21371c"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ……………………….. more money, I could buy a car.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "had had"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "dcaad4e0c54442dd98ee018b0e9adf4e"
        },
        {
            "question": "If it rains, we …………………………….. get wet.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "could"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "a24ede34152748fd911b726fe13f2f9d"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I …………………………. you, I would not tolerate this.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "were",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "03e11de7576c442bb4ce81a892af81f2"
        },
        {
            "question": "Had I seen the signal, I …………………………...",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will stop",
                "would stop",
                "would have stopped"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ab9c698fc44f42cdbc2b086d875d1e9d"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had told me you were not coming, I ……………………………… waited for you.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "won't have",
                "wouldn't have",
                "couldn't have"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bcc2a8fecaad495bab96ea11d65ccabc"
        },
        {
            "question": "If they had found him early, he …………………………….. saved.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will be",
                "would be",
                "would have been"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ed9ed4bcf9174da7a56e26a126e3673a"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she hadn’t married him, she …………………………….. happy.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will be",
                "would be",
                "would have been"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "90d493b1037e45159297ca029c88f55d"
        }
    ]
}